<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<registry>
  <title>Service Name and Transport Protocol Port Number Registry</title>
  <category>Service Names and Transport Protocol Port Numbers</category>
  <updated>2014-02-14</updated>
  <expert>TCP/UDP: Joe Touch; Eliot Lear, Allison Mankin, Markku Kojo, Kumiko Ono, Martin Stiemerling, Lars Eggert, Alexey Melnikov and Wes Eddy; 
    DCCP: Eddie Kohler; SCTP: Allison Mankin</expert>
  <note>
Service names and port numbers are used to distinguish between different
services that run over transport protocols such as TCP, UDP, DCCP, and
SCTP.

Service names are assigned on a first-come, first-served process, as
documented in.

Port numbers are assigned in various ways, based on three ranges: System
Ports (0-1023), User Ports (1024-49151), and the Dynamic and/or Private
Ports (49152-65535); the difference uses of these ranges is described in
System Ports are assigned by IETF
process for standards-track protocols, as per.  User Ports
are assigned by IANA using the "IETF Review" process, the "IESG 
Approval" process, or the "Expert Review" process, as per
Dynamic Ports are not assigned.

The registration procedures for service names and port numbers are
described in.

Assigned ports both System and User ports SHOULD NOT be used without
or prior to IANA registration.

************************************************************************
* PLEASE NOTE THE FOLLOWING:                                           *
*                                                                      *
* ASSIGNMENT OF A PORT NUMBER DOES NOT IN ANY WAY IMPLY AN             *
* ENDORSEMENT OF AN APPLICATION OR PRODUCT, AND THE FACT THAT NETWORK  *
* TRAFFIC IS FLOWING TO OR FROM A REGISTERED PORT DOES NOT MEAN THAT   *
* IT IS "GOOD" TRAFFIC, NOR THAT IT NECESSARILY CORRESPONDS TO THE     *
* ASSIGNED SERVICE. FIREWALL AND SYSTEM ADMINISTRATORS SHOULD          *
* CHOOSE HOW TO CONFIGURE THEIR SYSTEMS BASED ON THEIR KNOWLEDGE OF    *
* THE TRAFFIC IN QUESTION, NOT WHETHER THERE IS A PORT NUMBER          *
* REGISTERED OR NOT.                                                   *
************************************************************************</note>
  <record>
    <protocol>tcp</protocol>
    <xref type="person" data="Jon_Postel"/>
    <description>Reserved</description>
    <number>0</number>
  </record>
  <record>
    <protocol>udp</protocol>
    <xref type="person" data="Jon_Postel"/>
    <description>Reserved</description>
    <number>0</number>
  </record>
  <record>
    <name>tcpmux</name>
    <protocol>tcp</protocol>
    <xref type="person" data="Mark_Lottor"/>
    <description>TCP Port Service Multiplexer</description>
    <number>1</number>
  </record>
  </registry>